ROB SCHWITZER

Software Developer

robschwitzer@gmail.com 1-604-217-7338

Vancouver, BC

Fluent in JavaScript and well versed in modern frameworks, I am an experienced front end engineer who takes pride in delivering clean, scalable, and maintainable code on time, while pushing the envelope to explore new technologies to help meet business goals. With a background in music, I take a creative, outside-the-box approach to problem solving, while being dedicated to staying within the bounds of best practices as outlined by documentation. Over the past year, I have expanded my skill set by interviewing and hiring for developer positions, as well as providing guidance and mentorship to junior developers through code reviews and pair programming. Since graduating from Lighthouse Labs in 2018, I have thrived working remotely in a startup environment, but am just as comfortable showing up to an office (as long as there are snacks).

EXPERIENCE

Sphere | Lead Developer — March 2021 - Present

As the lead developer at Sphere, I have been responsible for interviewing, hiring, and guiding developers on their path to success, while simultaneously developing and maintaining numerous React, React Native, and NextJs codebases using GraphQL and REST apis. I participate in setting up and executing sprints, project planning and management, and working with designers to ensure that the product meets the specifications. I am solely responsible for managing the releases of the company's flagship product to the App Store and Play Store, as well as parsing analytics from both sources for use by customer success teams.

Lighthouse Labs | Web Development Mentor — October 2020 - Present

In this role, I meet with adult students of all ages and backgrounds several times a week to help them tackle problems that they encounter in the 12-week full stack development bootcamp. I strive to give people a better understanding of JavaScript, to demystify React, and to give students helpful advice as they embark on a new career in the software industry. I find it incredibly fulfilling to watch the transformation of students from struggling with basic JavaScript concepts, to presenting their full stack apps at the end of the program.

Sphere | Front End Developer — April 2019 - March 2021

In my time as a front end developer at Sphere, I was tasked with developing and maintaining all of the company's browser based products. This included green-fielding the main marketing site, setting up sign up flows, and taking delivery of 2 large React apps from an agency, of which I would be the sole maintainer. In this role I was fortunate to have lots of early exposure to NextJS, which gave me a great foundation for understanding the framework. I became comfortable with browser apis, authentication, styling, and accessibility. 4x100 Lighthouse scores were a self imposed standard.

Sphere | Junior Developer — September 2018 - April 2019

Starting as a 3 month internship, my first developer role was working on a React Native project. With terrific mentorship, in a short amount of time I was able to learn the framework and tech stack enough to be offered a permanent position with the company. I worked on bug fixes and implementing new features, as well as occasionally hopping on the support channel to interact with customers.

EDUCATION

Lighthouse Labs | Web Development Diploma - 2018

LANGUAGES

- JavaScript / TypeScript
- HTML / CSS
- GraphQL
- Solidity

FRAMEWORKS

- React / React Native
- NextJS
- NodeJS

DATABASES

- Firebase
- MongoDB

CMS

- Strapi
- Sanity
- Ghost

INTERESTS

- Entrepreneurship
- Music
- Subculture
- Technology
- The Past
- The Future
- Travel

SUMMARY

With 4+ years of front-end development experience, I am eager to join a team that embraces diversity, organization, planning, and tactful execution. I bring a positive attitude, progressive thinking, and unwavering diligence when faced with difficult problems. It is a goal of mine to join an organization that shares similar values, while being committed to developing cutting edge technology products. I am happy to provide references that can speak to my skills, adaptability, and commitment to delivering my best on every project.